

Elijah Offutt

Software Developer / Front End Engineer / Javascript Advocate

Profile

I love technology. My focus has been on the more visual and user experience side of the technological development spectrum, but, I am obsessed with how things get created from click to circuit. As a developer, I bring that curiosity and obsession to you in ways that express themselves in optimization and efficient application creation.

Contact

Phone (301)832-6875 Email Einzenheim@yahoo.com linkedin /in/witheringking Website elijahoffutt.github.io Github /ElijahOffutt Area Temple Hills MD

Skills

Web JS Cloud Programing Problem Solving Communication Security Leadership Teaching

Education

Bachelor of Science Degree in Web Design and Development 2014-2017 Full Sail University, in Arlington Virginia

At full sail, I learned the fundamentals of programming with a focus on web development which included such disciplines as full-stack development, APIs, schema building and front end frameworks.

Experience

UX Engineer 2018-2021

Leidos, in Reston Virginia

Here at Leidos I work on primarily UI focused tasked but I am also getting my hands in to the full stack of technologies for industrial solutions and coding disciplines such as back end and full stack engineering. Research and Development is proving to be a great place to really hone and expand my skill set as a developer and engineer.

Front End Developer

2017-2018

Bloomberg BNA (Now Bloomberg Industry Group), in Crystal City VA

I assisted, oversaw and developed assets as well as maintained and created methodologies that implemented test and data driven design. Leveraging technologies like Vue js and marketing software like Eloqua, I solved day to day problems within the front facing and marketing aspects of the company.

CMS Specialist and Developer

2016-2017

Ritz Carlton Corp, in Chevy Chase Maryland

At the Ritz Carlton, my duties are to handle several aspects of the direct content for their main website RitzCarlton.com. I assist and create methodologies as well as protocols to optimize the best solutions for their varied forms of content. I use my web development capabilities to develop digital tools and solutions for complex problems.